Bigyan Dahal

bigyandahal.com \cdot contact.bigyanse@gmail.com \cdot (+977) 9860701879 \cdot Kathmandu, Nepal

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer specializing in web development (both frontend and backend). I have experience in developing dynamic, optimized and performant web solutions. I am also experienced with various programming languages and technologies, including Node.js, PHP, Python, ReactJS, and more.

EXPERIENCE

THE VALUE CREW

Oct 2023 - Present

Web Developer

- Dynamic Quotation System: Quotation System for internal use
- GoPenAI Community: ChatGPT prompt sharing and interaction within the community
- The Star Tutor: Theme development, deployment and performance and search optimization

NEPAL HEALTH CORPS

OCT 2022 - OCT 2023

Web Developer

- Website Setup and Deployment
 - Website and Content Management
- Website Optimization

SKILLS

- Familiar with Node.js, PHP, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, ReactJS, Express, Django, Flask, TypeScript, C, C++, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, and MongoDB
- Proficient in Linux, System Administration, CI/CD, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify
- Familiar with Docker, Kubernetes and Cloud Computing
- WordPress Development and Deployment including Theme Development
- Understanding of Agile methodology, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), and different programming paradigms (OOP, functional, procedural)
- Knowledge of document preparation system: LaTeX

AWARDS

- First Position in Python Bytes 2021 organized by Advanced Robotics Club(ARC)
- Third Position in Provathon Purbanchal 2021 organized by CSIT Association of Nepal

EDUCATION

Advanced College of Engineering and Management

2019 - 2024